TYLER WORD

Portfolio: https://tylerword-33fbe.web.app

517 Temple St. Woodville, TX 75979 · 828-734-4514 · tcword89@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-word-7a50281a4/ https://github.com/tcword

A creative and engaging Full Stack Developer with a passion for front-end and back-end development. Maintains a commitment to exceed expectations with strong developer and interpersonal skills. Specializes in teamwork and customer satisfaction by honoring and serving others. With experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Redux, Angular, Express, Bootstrap, MongoDB, MySQL, and NoSQL, I am pursuing opportunities to provide programming skills, leadership ability, and enthusiasm to a fast paced environment as Web Developer.

SKILLS

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | TypeScript | jQuery | Bootstrap | ES6 | Angular | React | Redux | NoSQL | MySQL | SQL server | Node | Express | MongoDB | Passport | Firebase | Visual Studio Code | GitHub | Trello | NPM | Responsive Web Design | Dependency Injection | Web API | REST | AJAX | JSON | Cordova and Ionic | Agile Project Management | Agile Methodologies | Scrum

LATEST PROJECTS

myChat: https://whatsapp-47a9b.web.app

- REACT APPLICATION WITH FIREBASE SERVING AS THE BACKEND
- SLEEK WEBSITE DESIGN.
- UTILIZATION OF FIREBASE GOOGLE AUTHENTICATION.
- REACT CONTEXT API.
- USER IS ABLE TO CREATE A CHAT ROOM AND POST A MESSAGE IN REAL TIME.

iChat: https://social-d1a3c.web.app

- REACT APPLICATION WITH FIREBASE SERVING AS THE BACKEND.
- SLEEK WEBSITE DESIGN.
- UTILIZATION OF FIREBASE GOOGLE AUTHENTICATION.
- REACT CONTEXT API.
- USER IS ABLE TO POST A MESSAGE IN REAL TIME.

Netflix Clone: https://netflix-fc691.web.app

- REACT APPLICATION.
- RESPONSIVE SLEEK WEBSITE DESIGN.
- UTILIZATION OF THE MOVIE DATABASE API.

INTERACTIVE YOUTUBE TRAILERS THROUGH REACT-YOUTUBE.

Airbnb Clone: https://airbnb-71813.web.app

- REACT PROJECT WITH FIREBASE
- UTILIZED A DATE RANGE COMPONENT SO THE USER CAN USE AN INTERACTIVE CALENDER.
- UTILIZED REACT ROUTER FOR SMOOTH NAVIGATION SO THAT THE PAGE DOESN'T NEED TO LOAD WHEN NAVIGATING.
- INTERACTIVE ICONS AND IMAGES FOR A SLEEK MODERN FEEL.

EDUCATION

FEB 2020 - SEPT 2020

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT, BETHEL SCHOOL OF TECHNOLOGY

- BETHEL SCHOOL OF TECHNOLOGY, POWERED BY WOZU, APPLE'S CO-FOUNDER STEVE WOZNIAK.
- VOTED TOP CODING BOOTCAMP IN THE NATION -<u>HTTPS://WWW.NEWSWEEK.COM/INSIGHTS/THE-TOP-CODING-SCHOOLS-OF-2019/BETHEL-SCHOOL-TECHNOLOGY</u>
- LEARNED HOW TO BUILD ROBUST WEB APPLICATIONS USING JAVASCRIPT, REACT, AND ANGULAR.
- BUILT DATABASE-DRIVEN WEB APPLICATIONS USING NODE.JS AND MONGODB.
- CREATED RICHLY INTERACTIVE CLIENT-SIDE APPS USING THE JAVASCRIPT REACT.JS LIBRARY.

AUG. 2007 - MAY 2012

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN KINESIOLOGY, LAMAR UNIVERSITY

- RECEIVED THE STUDENT OF THE YEAR AWARD IN 2010.
- GRADUATED MAGNA CUM LAUDE.

EXPERIENCE

JULY 2016 – JULY 2020

TEACHER/COACH, WOODVILLE ISD

- LESSON PLAN IMPLEMENTATION AND INSTRUCTOR FOR OVER 400 STUDENTS EACH DAY.
- IMPLEMENTED INTERDISCIPLINARY CURRICULUM TO HELP FACILITATE LEARNING IN OTHER SUBJECT AREAS.
- COACHED TENNIS WITH 3 STATE TOURNAMENT APPEARANCES IN 3 YEARS.

JULY 2012 – JULY 2016 TEACHER/COACH, JASPER ISD

- LESSON PLAN IMPLEMENTATION AND INSTRUCTOR FOR OVER 200 STUDENTS EACH DAY.
- ASSISTANT COACH IN FOOTBALL, BASKETBALL, AND BASEBALL. HEAD COACH FOR VARSITY SOCCER AND TENNIS.